## **CONTACT MEAT**



Stockton, CA



smjot.singh@gmail.com



https://www.linkedin.com/in/sa mjot-s-a189831a1/

## CORESKILLS

- •••• React.js/Redux
- • Node/Express
- •••• Next.js
- •••• Vue.js
- •••• JavaScript
- • • Typescript
- • WordPress

# SAMJOT SINGH

## SENIOR FULLSTACK ENGINEER

## PERSONAL PROFILE

I am an enthusiastic and highly-driven individual, with a strong work ethic and dedication to producing results of the utmost quality. I have strong capabilities in web programming and implementation, based upon organizational talent acquisition needs.

My ideal career involves building software to help people become better at what they do.

I have experience working with languages/frameworks such as HTML, CSS, Typescript, JavaScript, React, Redux, Next.js, Vue, Node.js, Express.js, GraphQL, Apollo, WordPress.

From optimizing single-page web applications to successfully implementing company-wide system updates I've gained valuable hands- on experience meeting client's business requirements and fulfilling brand- building needs.

Typescript and JavaScript are my favorite languages.

I am always open to and excited about learning new technologies and building impactful applications.

#### -- MY DEVELOPMENT SKILLS --

- Languages: JavaScript, Typescript, HTML, CSS, SQL
- Frameworks: React, Redux, Next. js, Vue, Node, Express, WordPress
- Database System: Postgres, MYSQL, MongoDB, MS Access, AWS DynamoDB
- Version Control: Git, SVN
- Others:GraphQL(Apollo),REST,AWS,Firebase,GoogleCloudPlatform and Heroku, Redis, Agile(Scrum), Trello, Asana, Jira, Docker, Jenkins

#### -- MY PERSONAL SKILLS --

- Able to work on my own or with a team.
- Clear and effective communication skills.
- Having a well thought out approach to problems.
- Ability to follow complex instructions.
- Good time management skills, prioritization skills.
- Can work efficiently with minimum supervision.
- Able to meet tight deadlines.
- Pay attention todetail.
- Willing to go the 'extra mile' to get things done.

Thank you

## CONTACTMEAT



Stockton, CA



smjot.singh@gmail.com



https://www.linkedin.com/in/s amjot-s-a189831a1/

#### CORESKILLS

- •••• React.js/Redux
- • Node/Express
- • Next.js
- •••• Vue.js
- •••• JavaScript
- •••• Typescript
- ••• WordPress

## WORK EXPERIENCE

## Senior FullStack Engineer

Metlife \* Contract | Jan 2022 – July 2022

- Tech Stacks: Typescript, React, Node, Jest, Azure
- Helped manage application's technology platform status, project pipeline and development priorities.
- Redesigned and developed the user interface and converted figma into the UI.
- Reviewed project specifications and designed technology solutions that exceeded performance expectations.

## Full Stack Developer

iTechArt Group \* Contract | San Francisco, CA | Jan 2021 – Jan 2022

- Worked closely with project managers, VP of Engineering and CTO to meet deadlines and ensure the product fulfilled clients expectations.
- Lead and coach a team of junior engineers to create an application from scratch to production.
- Created and facilitated coding standards companywide to ensure all projects followed uniform guidelines of development.
- Worked on multiple code bases simultaneously, committing bug fixes and pushing each to a live production environment.

## Full Stack Developer

Vincit \* Full Time | Irvine, CA | Jan 2018 – Jan 2021

- Built full scale web applications from the ground up using React, Node.
- Resolved legacy code base bugs and pushed to a live production environment.
- Added new features to pre-existing web applications.
- Implemented intricate mockup designs with a variety of front-end languages.
- Executed and contributed to full stack development, browser manipulation and cross-browser compatibility

## Software Developer

Baytech Consulting \* Full Time | Jun 2016 – Jan 2018

- Building stable and maintainable codebases using React.
- Implementing a mobile-first approach to existing websites.
- Collaborating with designers to ensure designs were efficient and technically sound.
- Creating modular, responsive templates using modern CSS techniques and JavaScript libraries.
- Assisting with the transition from a waterfall method to a more efficient Agile methodology.

#### EDUCATIONALHISTORY

### **San Jose State University**

• Bachelor's degree in Computer Science, 2015